Alan Quintero

San Jose, CA - se.alan.quintero@outlook.com

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience, specializing in back-end development. Background includes IT Consulting, Insurance, Media, Health Care/Medical Solutions, Food Industry, and Web Design Solutions.

Committed to learning every day in order to expand my personal and technical skills.

Experience

Software Engineer at Bind, San Francisco, CA, 05/2020 to Present

- *Healthcare Insurance Industry*: working on the back-end to implement new functionality in the web application.

Technologies involved: Java 11, Spring Boot, Gradle, AWS, Jenkins, Sumo Logic, Git

Software Engineer at Zume, Mountain View, CA, 09/2019 to 03/2020

- *Food Industry*: worked on the back-end development to implement RESTful web microservices and worked on the front-end to create an internal web application.
- Created a web application using VueJS to present demos to potential clients in order to show the customer pickup workflow.
- Developed micro-services using TypeScript / JavaScript and ExpressJS for the customer pickup service.

<u>Technologies involved</u>: TypeScript / JavaScript, ExpressJS, VueJS, Jest, Redis, Git, JSON

Software Engineer at Talix, San Francisco, CA, 09/2018 to 08/2019

- *Healthcare Industry*: worked on the back-end development using Java to improve and maintain the new release of a text recognition tool.
- Increased the accuracy of the recognition of medical concepts by 5% by implementing an alpha sort algorithm for concepts within 5 to 7 words.
- Implemented algorithms to recognize special characters, increasing the precision recognition of medical concepts by 3%

Technologies involved: Java 7, J2EE, JUnit, Apache OpenNLP, CVS, Oracle SQL, Tomcat

Technology Analyst at Infosys, Sunnyvale, CA, 06/2017 - 09/2018

- Client: Apple
 - *Internal Infrastructure*: worked on the back-end development to implement a RESTful Java application used as a middleware to execute a Scala Application.
 - I worked on a project in which I used an internal framework to create RESTful web services, I used Java to call another application in Scala. I had to work with the data to build the input of the Scala application and also to generate the output of the Java application, I applied algorithms to build the inputs/outputs in an optimal time.
 - I was in charge of the Java application and I was the only one who worked on it. The clients only explained the requirements and I had to implement all the code, they did not check my coding style, they just verified that the application fulfilled the expected performance.

<u>Technologies involved</u>: Java 8, J2EE, RESTful, Maven, JSON, JUnit 4, Mockito, Git, Apache Tomcat

Software Engineering Sr. Analyst at Accenture, Monterrey, MX, 08/2016 - 06/2017

- Client: Charter
 - *Mass Media Industry:* worked on the back-end development to create a RESTful Java application using Spring Boot.
 - Was in charge of the back-end team. Helped with the design of web services, designed JSON request/response, code reviews, created unit and integration tests.
 - I volunteered myself to learn Selenium in order to help the tester with the work overload
 - Even though the team was working remotely, we managed to coordinate efficiently to meet delivery times.

<u>Technologies involved</u>: Java 8, J2EE, Spring Boot, Spring Security, RESTful, JDBC, Hibernate, Maven, JUnit 4, Mockito, Selenium 2, Git, MySQL, Teradata, Sonar, Tomcat, Jenkins, JSON, XML, Swagger

Java Developer at Tata Consultancy Services, Guadalajara, MX, 04/2015 - 08/2016

- Client: USAA
 - *Health and Insurance Industry*: worked on the back-end development to implement a new line of business for a web application.
 - Proposed changing the validations to be in each step of the claim process instead of having them at the final step, to avoid going back and forward within the process. It improved the user experience by facilitating the usage of the claims process.
 - Organized and conducted a Java training for interns. Created an internal tool to book conference rooms. The tool has been used by more than 200 employees.

<u>Technologies involved</u>: Java 6, J2EE, Spring MVC 3, Maven 3, RESTful, JUnit 4, JSON, Hibernate, JDBC, Git, Jetty, Sonar, Oracle SQL

Education

Universidad Autonoma de Aguascalientes. Aguascalientes, MX

B.S. in Computer Systems Engineering

Portfolio

GitHub: https://github.com/alanquintero

Personal Website: http://alanquintero.com.mx